<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Salut, je m&#39;appelle Étienne on Blogue d&#39;Étienne</title>
    <link>https://www.etienne.ninja/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Salut, je m&#39;appelle Étienne on Blogue d&#39;Étienne</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>fr-ca</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 12:20:27 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.etienne.ninja/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>De zéro à millionnaire</title>
      <link>https://www.etienne.ninja/de-z%C3%A9ro-%C3%A0-millionnaire/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 12:20:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.etienne.ninja/de-z%C3%A9ro-%C3%A0-millionnaire/</guid>
      <description>L’investisseur Warren Buffett a acheté sa maison actuelle à Omaha, au Nebraska, en 1958. Il l’a payée 31 500 $. Sa propriété est aujourd’hui évaluée à 700 000 $. Mais s’il avait plutôt investi ses 31 500 $ dans le marché boursier, ce placement vaudrait aujourd’hui plus de 23 millions de dollars.
 Penser est facile. Agir est difficile. Mais la chose la plus difficile au monde est d’agir en accord avec sa pensée.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Human hacking</title>
      <link>https://www.etienne.ninja/human-hacking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 12:20:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.etienne.ninja/human-hacking/</guid>
      <description>I just launched that joke with the attendant and other passengers within earshot, not knowing who would respond and “catch” the softball. Whoever did would become my “target,” or as I also call it in this book, my “person of interest.”
 when mastered, will allow you to win friends, influence people, and achieve most goals you might have—all by being kinder, more empathetic, and more giving.
 You must make a habit of getting outside of your own head, imagining what the other person is thinking and engaging with them in ways that respect and address their needs, beliefs, and emotions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes Hardening Guide</title>
      <link>https://www.etienne.ninja/kubernetes-hardening-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 12:20:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.etienne.ninja/kubernetes-hardening-guide/</guid>
      <description>My notes from this ressources: https://media.defense.gov/2021/Aug/03/2002820425/-1/-1/0/CTR_Kubernetes_Hardening_Guidance_1.1_20220315.PDF
 -&amp;gt; Supply chain risks are often challenging to mitigate and can arise in the container build cycle or infrastructure acquisition. -&amp;gt; Malicious threat actors can exploit vulnerabilities and misconfigurations in components of the Kubernetes architecture, such as the control plane, worker nodes, or containerized applications. -&amp;gt; Insider threats can be administrators, users, or cloud service providers. Insiders with special access to an organization’s Kubernetes nfrastructure may be able to abuse these privileges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Le cygne noir</title>
      <link>https://www.etienne.ninja/le-cygne-noir/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 12:20:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.etienne.ninja/le-cygne-noir/</guid>
      <description>Je restai donc dans la finance quantitative et le trading (j’y suis encore), mais m’organisai pour travailler un minimum – mais intensément (et en m’amusant) –, me concentrer uniquement sur les aspects les plus techniques de mon métier, ne jamais assister aux « réunions », éviter la compagnie des « gagnants » et des hommes en costumes qui ne lisent jamais de livres, et prendre une année sabbatique en moyenne tous les trois ans pour combler les lacunes de ma culture scientifique et philosophique.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mais qui a attrapé le bison de Higgs?</title>
      <link>https://www.etienne.ninja/mais-qui-a-attrap%C3%A9-le-bison-de-higgs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 12:20:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.etienne.ninja/mais-qui-a-attrap%C3%A9-le-bison-de-higgs/</guid>
      <description>la théorie dite de la panspermie, selon laquelle les premières cellules vivantes auraient pu arriver sur Terre dans des météorites.
 si l’atmosphère terrestre n’avait pas toujours été ce qu’elle est aujourd’hui ? Et si, il y a 3,5 milliards d’années, elle avait été dépourvue d’oxygène ? Dans ces conditions, les molécules de base du vivant auraient pu se former et s’assembler sans être dégradées
 le contenu de la fiole et détecta la présence d’au moins onze types de molécules différentes appartenant à la famille des acides aminés : les briques chimiques élémentaires de la vie telle que nous la connaissons sur Terre…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mastering Azure Security</title>
      <link>https://www.etienne.ninja/mastering-azure-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 12:20:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.etienne.ninja/mastering-azure-security/</guid>
      <description>two different network architectures in Azure datacenters – Default LAN Architecture (DLA) and Quantum 10 Architecture (Q10)
 Each cluster contains around 1,000 VMs. All VMs are managed by the FabricController (FC).
 Establishment of policies, and continuous monitoring of their proper implementation, by the members of the governing body of an organization.
 If you want to make sure that all environments will strictly adhere to your rules, automatic deployments are your way to go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nudge: Improving Decisions About Health, Wealth, and Happiness</title>
      <link>https://www.etienne.ninja/nudge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 12:20:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.etienne.ninja/nudge/</guid>
      <description>Simply by rearranging the cafeteria, Carolyn was able to increase or decrease the consumption of many food items by as much as 25 percent.
 school children, like adults, can be greatly influenced by small changes in the context
 There the authorities have etched the image of a black housefly into each urinal. It seems that men usually do not pay much attention to where they aim, which can create a bit of a mess, but if they see a target, attention and therefore accuracy are much increased</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Geometry of Wealth: How to shape a life of money and meaning</title>
      <link>https://www.etienne.ninja/the-geometry-of-wealth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 12:20:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.etienne.ninja/the-geometry-of-wealth/</guid>
      <description>In 1979, General Motors employed 840,000 people and earned profits of about $11 billion. Meanwhile, in 2012, Google employed less than 38,000 people and generated profits of nearly $14 billion. In case you’re wondering, these profits are adjusted for inflation.15 So on an apples-to-apples basis, the labor necessary to produce great profits has plummeted. In this case, there were comparable profits, but fewer than one-twentieth the jobs.
 Our job is to find a few intelligent things to do, not to keep up with every damn thing in the world</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Think Again</title>
      <link>https://www.etienne.ninja/think-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 12:20:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.etienne.ninja/think-again/</guid>
      <description>Yet in a turbulent world, there’s another set of cognitive skills that might matter more: the ability to rethink and unlearn.
 It’s not the frogs who fail to reevaluate. It’s us. Once we hear the story and accept it as true, we rarely bother to question it.
 Our ways of thinking become habits that can weigh us down, and we don’t bother to question them until it’s too late</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>(DRAFT) La sécurité des API</title>
      <link>https://www.etienne.ninja/securityapi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2021 12:20:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.etienne.ninja/securityapi/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Avant de vous lancer dans la lecture, assurez-vous de bien comprendre certains principes de sécurité pour suivre. Ce n’est pas un article accessible aux nouveaux en sécurité. Le livre est une combinaison de théorie et de pratique. Je n’expliquerai pas les étapes de développement et de déploiement d’un API avec un framework comme l’explique le livre.
Le livre commence avec une petite introduction aux vieilles applications legacy dites &amp;ldquo;monolithique&amp;rdquo;. La majorité des applications monolithiques ont quelques points d&amp;rsquo;entrées seulement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced API Security OAuth 2.0 And Beyond</title>
      <link>https://www.etienne.ninja/advanced-api-security-oauth-2.0-and-beyond/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 12:20:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.etienne.ninja/advanced-api-security-oauth-2.0-and-beyond/</guid>
      <description>JSON Web Encryption (JWE) and JSON Web Signature (JWS) are two increasingly popular standards for securing JSON messages.
 REST (JSON over HTTP).
 naked API is an unmanaged API. An unmanaged API has its own deficiencies
 A comprehensive API management platform needs to have at least three main components: a publisher, a store, and a gateway (see Figure 1-9)
 The API publisher provides tooling support to create and publish API</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Atomic Habits: Tiny Changes, Remarkable Results</title>
      <link>https://www.etienne.ninja/atomic-habits-tiny-changes-remarkable-results/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 12:20:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.etienne.ninja/atomic-habits-tiny-changes-remarkable-results/</guid>
      <description>a strategy that he referred to as “the aggregation of marginal gains,” which was the philosophy of searching for a tiny margin of improvement in everything you do.
 Why do small improvements accumulate into such remarkable results, and how can you replicate this approach in your own life?
 improving by 1 percent isn’t particularly notable—sometimes it isn’t even noticeable—but it can be far more meaningful, especially in the long run</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Factfulness - Ten Reasons We&#39;re Wrong About the World – and Why Things Are Better Than You Think</title>
      <link>https://www.etienne.ninja/factfulness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 12:20:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.etienne.ninja/factfulness/</guid>
      <description>Through pure luck, the troop of chimps would score 33 percent on each three-answer question, or four out of the first 12 on the whole test. Remember that the humans I have tested get on average just two out of 12 on the same test.
 Often it takes several generations for a family to move from Level 1 to Level 4
 Just 200 years ago, 85 percent of the world population was still on Level 1, in extreme poverty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn Kubernetes Security</title>
      <link>https://www.etienne.ninja/learn-kubernetes-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 12:20:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.etienne.ninja/learn-kubernetes-security/</guid>
      <description>Comme j&amp;rsquo;ai lu le livre devant mon ordinateur et non sur mon téléphone, ce ne sont pas des highlights, mais des notes durant ma lecture.

 Chapitre 1. Kube réponds aux scaling, cout et les délais des cycle de déploiement. L&amp;rsquo;explosion des microservice amene une complexité aux devOps. différents language et interpreteur. différents packages, différentes config. C&amp;rsquo;est la que docker règle bien des problèmes. Docker Swarm est renommé Docker Enterprise Edition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Les micros habitudes</title>
      <link>https://www.etienne.ninja/les-micros-habitudes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 12:20:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.etienne.ninja/les-micros-habitudes/</guid>
      <description>Le livre Atomic habits est l&amp;rsquo;un des livres qui m&amp;rsquo;a le plus transformé.
Le livre commence par expliquer que les petites différences sont importante sur le long terme. Personne ne remarque si tu t&amp;rsquo;améliores d&amp;rsquo;un pourcent, mais les petits changements qui sont répété devienne significative sur plusieurs années. Par exemple:
 Si tu mets un peu d&amp;rsquo;argent de côté chaque semaine, tu ne deviens pas immédiatement financièrement indépendant. Tu n&amp;rsquo;es pas en forme après deux scéances de gym.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Liberté 45</title>
      <link>https://www.etienne.ninja/libert%C3%A9-45/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 12:20:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.etienne.ninja/libert%C3%A9-45/</guid>
      <description>l’exonération cumulative pour gain en capital
 As-tu un plan B ? As-tu un autre plan A ?
 En un mot, dépenser pour quelque chose, c’est renoncer à autre chose.
 plus tu vieillis, moins le coût de renonciation est grand et moins il est illogique de dépenser.
 Si on dépense le même dollar à 34 ans, on se prive plutôt de 3,56 $ à 60 ans.
 Pas étonnant que certaines personnes de la région d’Ottawa qui songent à avoir des enfants décident d’élire domicile au Québec à cause des avantages fiscaux alloués par notre province.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lifecycle investing a new, safe, and audacious way to improve the performance of your retirement portfolio</title>
      <link>https://www.etienne.ninja/lifecycle-investing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 12:20:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.etienne.ninja/lifecycle-investing/</guid>
      <description>Over the last 138 years, stocks have outper-formed bonds—not every year, but for every generation. On average, stocks have outperformed bonds by 5 percent.
 Of course, low fees also mean low ad budgets. If you see a firm spending loads of money trying to convince you to invest with them, you should realize that it will be your money that’s paying for the ads.
 A good way to measure risk is by the range of outcomes that you’ll see 95 percent of the time</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Limitless</title>
      <link>https://www.etienne.ninja/limitless/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 12:20:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.etienne.ninja/limitless/</guid>
      <description>Limitless teaches us the five key methods to achieve whatever we want: Focus, Study, Memory Enhancement, Speed Reading, and Critical Thinking
 Learning how to learn is the ultimate superpower, the one that makes every other skill and ability possible, and teaching this to you is this book’s goal.
 Often when you put a label on someone or something, you create a limit—the label becomes the limitation
 “No problem can be solved from the same level of consciousness that created it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux basics for hackers</title>
      <link>https://www.etienne.ninja/linux-basics-for-hackers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 12:20:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.etienne.ninja/linux-basics-for-hackers/</guid>
      <description>locate uses a database that is usually only updated once a day, so if you just created a file a few minutes or a few hours ago, it might not appear in this list until the next day.
 The ? wildcard is used to represent a single character, so a search for ?at would find hat, cat, and bat but not what, because at in this filename is preceded by two letters</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microservices Security in Action</title>
      <link>https://www.etienne.ninja/microservices-security-in-action/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 12:20:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.etienne.ninja/microservices-security-in-action/</guid>
      <description>Each microservice runs in its own container, and as a best practice, the container has to be an immutable server.3 In other words, after the container has spun up, it shouldn’t change any of the files in its filesystem or maintain any runtime state within the container itself.
 You need a way to verify that the user context passed among microservices isn’t deliberately modified
 This architecture, which enables the various components in a system to pick the technology stack that is best for them, is known as a polyglot architecture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Official Google Cloud Certified Associate Cloud Engineer</title>
      <link>https://www.etienne.ninja/official-google-cloud-certified-associate-cloud-engineer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 12:20:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.etienne.ninja/official-google-cloud-certified-associate-cloud-engineer/</guid>
      <description>The fl ashcards in the TestBank will push the limits of what you should know for the cer-tif i cation exam
 log sinks to export logs to external systems
 Autoscalers can add or remove VMs from the cluster based on the workload. This is called autoscaling.
 Managed clusters make use of containers. A container is like a lightweight VM that isolates processes running in one container from processes running in another container on the same server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practical Cloud Security A Guide for Secure Design and Deployment</title>
      <link>https://www.etienne.ninja/practical-cloud-security-a-guide-for-secure-design-and-deployment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 12:20:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.etienne.ninja/practical-cloud-security-a-guide-for-secure-design-and-deployment/</guid>
      <description>If you are in a very high security environment and your threat model includes protecting data in memory from a privileged user, you should seek out a platform that supports memory encryption; it goes by brand names such as Intel SGX, AMD SME, and IBM Z Pervasive Encryption.
 You must track who has access to the private keys, because these individuals have the ability to impersonate your site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Obesity Code Secrets of Weight Loss</title>
      <link>https://www.etienne.ninja/the-obesity-code-secrets-of-weight-loss/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 12:20:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.etienne.ninja/the-obesity-code-secrets-of-weight-loss/</guid>
      <description>Mon résumé Je retiens qu&amp;rsquo;il y a trois actions qu&amp;rsquo;il suggère pour la perte de poids:
 Éviter tout ce qui est sucre raffiné et glucides raffinés (pâte, pain, chips, chocolat) Arrêter de manger entre les repas Faire des jeunes sur de courtes périodes.  J&amp;rsquo;ai déjà coupé le sucre durant 8 mois et je n&amp;rsquo;ai eu aucune perte significative. J&amp;rsquo;ai appliqué un seul conseil du livre: je mange à ma faim (même énormément), mais seulement aux repas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Subtle Art of Not Giving a F*ck</title>
      <link>https://www.etienne.ninja/the-subtle-art-of-not-giving-a-fck/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 12:20:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.etienne.ninja/the-subtle-art-of-not-giving-a-fck/</guid>
      <description>Everything worthwhile in life is won through surmounting the associated negative experience
 We suffer for the simple reason that suffering is biologically useful
 Life is essentially an endless series of problems, Mark
 The solution to one problem is merely the creation of the next one.”
 Happiness comes from solving problems. The keyword here is “solving.”
 negative emotions are a call to action
 Whatever makes us happy today will no longer make us happy tomorrow, because our biology always needs something more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Votre empire dans un sac à dos</title>
      <link>https://www.etienne.ninja/votre-empire-dans-un-sac-a-dos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 12:20:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.etienne.ninja/votre-empire-dans-un-sac-a-dos/</guid>
      <description>Gary Halbert est depuis devenu une figure mythique parmi les copywriters (cet anglicisme désigne un rédacteur spécialisé dans la vente – l’expression française équivalente est « concepteur-rédacteur »). Dans les années 1980, il a écrit une série de lettres à son fils
 Lors d’un entretien avec Shane Parrish, du podcast The Knowledge Project2 , il explique ces deux stratégies : « Vous devez vous poser la question : est-ce que je suis quelqu’un qui fait de la technique ?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why We Sleep: Unlocking the Power of Sleep and Dreams</title>
      <link>https://www.etienne.ninja/why-we-sleep-unlocking-the-power-of-sleep-and-dreams/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 12:20:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.etienne.ninja/why-we-sleep-unlocking-the-power-of-sleep-and-dreams/</guid>
      <description>Sleep further regulates our appetite, helping control body weight through healthy food selection rather than rash impulsivity
 this temperature rhythm is not dependent upon whether you are actually asleep. If I were to keep you awake all night, your core body temperature would still show the same pattern.
 Others are “evening types,” and account for approximately 30 percent of the population. They naturally prefer going to bed late and subsequently wake up late the following morning, or even in the afternoon</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protection de son identité numérique</title>
      <link>https://www.etienne.ninja/protection-de-sa-vie-num%C3%A9rique/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 12:16:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.etienne.ninja/protection-de-sa-vie-num%C3%A9rique/</guid>
      <description>Peut-être que vous aimeriez mieux protégez votre vie privée, mais vous ne savez pas par où commencer? Commencez par lire cette page. Nous avons tous une vie sur internet et pourtant la sécurité de cette identité est souvent négligée.
Je vous suggère deux étapes importantes pour corriger cette négligence.
 Étape 1 - Voute de mot de passe Si vous n&amp;rsquo;utilisez pas de voûte, vous utilisez probablement un &amp;ldquo;pattern&amp;rdquo; douteux facile à deviner pour la création de vos mots de passe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>À propos</title>
      <link>https://www.etienne.ninja/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.etienne.ninja/about/</guid>
      <description>Je suis un éternel étudiant, je cherche à simplifier ma vie, réduire mes possessions et je crois que le bonheur doit être présent aujourd&amp;rsquo;hui.
J&amp;rsquo;ai eu un réveil en septembre 2020. Après ma prise de conscience sur le temps que je perdais à ne rien faire d&amp;rsquo;utile, j&amp;rsquo;ai décidé de réduire ma consommation &amp;ldquo;d&amp;rsquo;internet&amp;rdquo; (dépendance à la dopamine) et avec la lecture du livre Atomic habits, j&amp;rsquo;ai tranquillement changé mon identité, j&amp;rsquo;ai ajouté des habitudes, et, une petite roche à la fois, ma vie s&amp;rsquo;est trouvée changée.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
