<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Argent on Blogue d&#39;Étienne</title>
    <link>https://main.d180cq1p10na41.amplifyapp.com/tags/argent/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Argent on Blogue d&#39;Étienne</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>fr-ca</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 12:20:27 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://main.d180cq1p10na41.amplifyapp.com/tags/argent/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>De zéro à millionnaire</title>
      <link>https://main.d180cq1p10na41.amplifyapp.com/de-z%C3%A9ro-%C3%A0-millionnaire/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 12:20:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://main.d180cq1p10na41.amplifyapp.com/de-z%C3%A9ro-%C3%A0-millionnaire/</guid>
      <description>L’investisseur Warren Buffett a acheté sa maison actuelle à Omaha, au Nebraska, en 1958. Il l’a payée 31 500 $. Sa propriété est aujourd’hui évaluée à 700 000 $. Mais s’il avait plutôt investi ses 31 500 $ dans le marché boursier, ce placement vaudrait aujourd’hui plus de 23 millions de dollars.
 Penser est facile. Agir est difficile. Mais la chose la plus difficile au monde est d’agir en accord avec sa pensée.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nudge: Improving Decisions About Health, Wealth, and Happiness</title>
      <link>https://main.d180cq1p10na41.amplifyapp.com/nudge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 12:20:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://main.d180cq1p10na41.amplifyapp.com/nudge/</guid>
      <description>Simply by rearranging the cafeteria, Carolyn was able to increase or decrease the consumption of many food items by as much as 25 percent.
 school children, like adults, can be greatly influenced by small changes in the context
 There the authorities have etched the image of a black housefly into each urinal. It seems that men usually do not pay much attention to where they aim, which can create a bit of a mess, but if they see a target, attention and therefore accuracy are much increased</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Geometry of Wealth: How to shape a life of money and meaning</title>
      <link>https://main.d180cq1p10na41.amplifyapp.com/the-geometry-of-wealth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 12:20:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://main.d180cq1p10na41.amplifyapp.com/the-geometry-of-wealth/</guid>
      <description>In 1979, General Motors employed 840,000 people and earned profits of about $11 billion. Meanwhile, in 2012, Google employed less than 38,000 people and generated profits of nearly $14 billion. In case you’re wondering, these profits are adjusted for inflation.15 So on an apples-to-apples basis, the labor necessary to produce great profits has plummeted. In this case, there were comparable profits, but fewer than one-twentieth the jobs.
 Our job is to find a few intelligent things to do, not to keep up with every damn thing in the world</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Liberté 45</title>
      <link>https://main.d180cq1p10na41.amplifyapp.com/libert%C3%A9-45/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 12:20:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://main.d180cq1p10na41.amplifyapp.com/libert%C3%A9-45/</guid>
      <description>l’exonération cumulative pour gain en capital
 As-tu un plan B ? As-tu un autre plan A ?
 En un mot, dépenser pour quelque chose, c’est renoncer à autre chose.
 plus tu vieillis, moins le coût de renonciation est grand et moins il est illogique de dépenser.
 Si on dépense le même dollar à 34 ans, on se prive plutôt de 3,56 $ à 60 ans.
 Pas étonnant que certaines personnes de la région d’Ottawa qui songent à avoir des enfants décident d’élire domicile au Québec à cause des avantages fiscaux alloués par notre province.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lifecycle investing a new, safe, and audacious way to improve the performance of your retirement portfolio</title>
      <link>https://main.d180cq1p10na41.amplifyapp.com/lifecycle-investing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 12:20:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://main.d180cq1p10na41.amplifyapp.com/lifecycle-investing/</guid>
      <description>Over the last 138 years, stocks have outper-formed bonds—not every year, but for every generation. On average, stocks have outperformed bonds by 5 percent.
 Of course, low fees also mean low ad budgets. If you see a firm spending loads of money trying to convince you to invest with them, you should realize that it will be your money that’s paying for the ads.
 A good way to measure risk is by the range of outcomes that you’ll see 95 percent of the time</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
