<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Général on Blogue d&#39;Étienne</title>
    <link>https://www.etienne.ninja/tags/g%C3%A9n%C3%A9ral/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Général on Blogue d&#39;Étienne</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>fr-ca</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 12:20:27 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.etienne.ninja/tags/g%C3%A9n%C3%A9ral/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Human hacking</title>
      <link>https://www.etienne.ninja/human-hacking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 12:20:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.etienne.ninja/human-hacking/</guid>
      <description>I just launched that joke with the attendant and other passengers within earshot, not knowing who would respond and “catch” the softball. Whoever did would become my “target,” or as I also call it in this book, my “person of interest.”
 when mastered, will allow you to win friends, influence people, and achieve most goals you might have—all by being kinder, more empathetic, and more giving.
 You must make a habit of getting outside of your own head, imagining what the other person is thinking and engaging with them in ways that respect and address their needs, beliefs, and emotions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Le cygne noir</title>
      <link>https://www.etienne.ninja/le-cygne-noir/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 12:20:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.etienne.ninja/le-cygne-noir/</guid>
      <description>Je restai donc dans la finance quantitative et le trading (j’y suis encore), mais m’organisai pour travailler un minimum – mais intensément (et en m’amusant) –, me concentrer uniquement sur les aspects les plus techniques de mon métier, ne jamais assister aux « réunions », éviter la compagnie des « gagnants » et des hommes en costumes qui ne lisent jamais de livres, et prendre une année sabbatique en moyenne tous les trois ans pour combler les lacunes de ma culture scientifique et philosophique.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Think Again</title>
      <link>https://www.etienne.ninja/think-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 12:20:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.etienne.ninja/think-again/</guid>
      <description>Yet in a turbulent world, there’s another set of cognitive skills that might matter more: the ability to rethink and unlearn.
 It’s not the frogs who fail to reevaluate. It’s us. Once we hear the story and accept it as true, we rarely bother to question it.
 Our ways of thinking become habits that can weigh us down, and we don’t bother to question them until it’s too late</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Atomic Habits: Tiny Changes, Remarkable Results</title>
      <link>https://www.etienne.ninja/atomic-habits-tiny-changes-remarkable-results/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 12:20:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.etienne.ninja/atomic-habits-tiny-changes-remarkable-results/</guid>
      <description>a strategy that he referred to as “the aggregation of marginal gains,” which was the philosophy of searching for a tiny margin of improvement in everything you do.
 Why do small improvements accumulate into such remarkable results, and how can you replicate this approach in your own life?
 improving by 1 percent isn’t particularly notable—sometimes it isn’t even noticeable—but it can be far more meaningful, especially in the long run</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Factfulness - Ten Reasons We&#39;re Wrong About the World – and Why Things Are Better Than You Think</title>
      <link>https://www.etienne.ninja/factfulness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 12:20:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.etienne.ninja/factfulness/</guid>
      <description>Through pure luck, the troop of chimps would score 33 percent on each three-answer question, or four out of the first 12 on the whole test. Remember that the humans I have tested get on average just two out of 12 on the same test.
 Often it takes several generations for a family to move from Level 1 to Level 4
 Just 200 years ago, 85 percent of the world population was still on Level 1, in extreme poverty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Les micros habitudes</title>
      <link>https://www.etienne.ninja/les-micros-habitudes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 12:20:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.etienne.ninja/les-micros-habitudes/</guid>
      <description>Le livre Atomic habits est l&amp;rsquo;un des livres qui m&amp;rsquo;a le plus transformé.
Le livre commence par expliquer que les petites différences sont importante sur le long terme. Personne ne remarque si tu t&amp;rsquo;améliores d&amp;rsquo;un pourcent, mais les petits changements qui sont répété devienne significative sur plusieurs années. Par exemple:
 Si tu mets un peu d&amp;rsquo;argent de côté chaque semaine, tu ne deviens pas immédiatement financièrement indépendant. Tu n&amp;rsquo;es pas en forme après deux scéances de gym.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Limitless</title>
      <link>https://www.etienne.ninja/limitless/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 12:20:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.etienne.ninja/limitless/</guid>
      <description>Limitless teaches us the five key methods to achieve whatever we want: Focus, Study, Memory Enhancement, Speed Reading, and Critical Thinking
 Learning how to learn is the ultimate superpower, the one that makes every other skill and ability possible, and teaching this to you is this book’s goal.
 Often when you put a label on someone or something, you create a limit—the label becomes the limitation
 “No problem can be solved from the same level of consciousness that created it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Obesity Code Secrets of Weight Loss</title>
      <link>https://www.etienne.ninja/the-obesity-code-secrets-of-weight-loss/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 12:20:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.etienne.ninja/the-obesity-code-secrets-of-weight-loss/</guid>
      <description>Mon résumé Je retiens qu&amp;rsquo;il y a trois actions qu&amp;rsquo;il suggère pour la perte de poids:
 Éviter tout ce qui est sucre raffiné et glucides raffinés (pâte, pain, chips, chocolat) Arrêter de manger entre les repas Faire des jeunes sur de courtes périodes.  J&amp;rsquo;ai déjà coupé le sucre durant 8 mois et je n&amp;rsquo;ai eu aucune perte significative. J&amp;rsquo;ai appliqué un seul conseil du livre: je mange à ma faim (même énormément), mais seulement aux repas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Subtle Art of Not Giving a F*ck</title>
      <link>https://www.etienne.ninja/the-subtle-art-of-not-giving-a-fck/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 12:20:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.etienne.ninja/the-subtle-art-of-not-giving-a-fck/</guid>
      <description>Everything worthwhile in life is won through surmounting the associated negative experience
 We suffer for the simple reason that suffering is biologically useful
 Life is essentially an endless series of problems, Mark
 The solution to one problem is merely the creation of the next one.”
 Happiness comes from solving problems. The keyword here is “solving.”
 negative emotions are a call to action
 Whatever makes us happy today will no longer make us happy tomorrow, because our biology always needs something more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Votre empire dans un sac à dos</title>
      <link>https://www.etienne.ninja/votre-empire-dans-un-sac-a-dos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 12:20:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.etienne.ninja/votre-empire-dans-un-sac-a-dos/</guid>
      <description>Gary Halbert est depuis devenu une figure mythique parmi les copywriters (cet anglicisme désigne un rédacteur spécialisé dans la vente – l’expression française équivalente est « concepteur-rédacteur »). Dans les années 1980, il a écrit une série de lettres à son fils
 Lors d’un entretien avec Shane Parrish, du podcast The Knowledge Project2 , il explique ces deux stratégies : « Vous devez vous poser la question : est-ce que je suis quelqu’un qui fait de la technique ?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why We Sleep: Unlocking the Power of Sleep and Dreams</title>
      <link>https://www.etienne.ninja/why-we-sleep-unlocking-the-power-of-sleep-and-dreams/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 12:20:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.etienne.ninja/why-we-sleep-unlocking-the-power-of-sleep-and-dreams/</guid>
      <description>Sleep further regulates our appetite, helping control body weight through healthy food selection rather than rash impulsivity
 this temperature rhythm is not dependent upon whether you are actually asleep. If I were to keep you awake all night, your core body temperature would still show the same pattern.
 Others are “evening types,” and account for approximately 30 percent of the population. They naturally prefer going to bed late and subsequently wake up late the following morning, or even in the afternoon</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protection de son identité numérique</title>
      <link>https://www.etienne.ninja/protection-de-sa-vie-num%C3%A9rique/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 12:16:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.etienne.ninja/protection-de-sa-vie-num%C3%A9rique/</guid>
      <description>Peut-être que vous aimeriez mieux protégez votre vie privée, mais vous ne savez pas par où commencer? Commencez par lire cette page. Nous avons tous une vie sur internet et pourtant la sécurité de cette identité est souvent négligée.
Je vous suggère deux étapes importantes pour corriger cette négligence.
 Étape 1 - Voute de mot de passe Si vous n&amp;rsquo;utilisez pas de voûte, vous utilisez probablement un &amp;ldquo;pattern&amp;rdquo; douteux facile à deviner pour la création de vos mots de passe.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
